Guide to the Page Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Family Papers, 1828-1948; Series II; 2.75' (7 boxes)
  - Page, Elizabeth Merwin Roe
    - Indian missions
      - Central American missions, 1919-1930, undated (Box 12, Folder 230)
      - In Camp and Tepee, 1915 (Box 12, Folder 231)
      - In Camp and Tepee, 1915 (Box 13, Folder 232)
      - In Camp and Tepee: Reviews, etc., 1915 (Box 13, Folder 233)
      - Indian scholarships, 1928-1932 (Box 13, Folder 234)
      - Latin American missions, 1926-1927 (Box 13, Folder 235)
      - Miscellaneous, 1906-1930, undated (Box 13, Folder 236)
      - News Bulletin of the Women's Board of Domestic Missions, 1929-1930 (Box 13, Folder 237)
      - Pamphlets and printed material, undated (Box 13, Folder 238)
      - Photographs, undated (Box 13, Folder 239)
      - "The Story of Our Indian Mission", undated (Box 13, Folder 240-242)
    - Inspirational prose and poetry, undated (Box 13, Folder 243)
    - Lake Bomoseen books, 1911-1927, undated (Box 14, Folder 244-245)
    - Lake Bomoseen lease, 1940 (Box 14, Folder 246)
    - "Marble Faun", undated (Box 14, Folder 247)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 14, Folder 248-249)
    - Recipes, undated (Box 14, Folder 250-251)
    - Writings collected by, 1894, 1935, undated (Box 14, Folder 252)
  - Page, Helen Wickham
    - Composition books, 1896-1897 (Box 14, Folder 253-254)
    - Spelling book, 1896 (Box 14, Folder 255)
  - Page, Henry: envelopes of California letters, 1849-1851 (Box 14, Folder 256)
  - Page, Mary A.: will, 1888 (Box 14, Folder 257)
  - Page, Mary Ann Reynolds: Memoir of Mrs. Mary Reynolds Page, 1873 (Box 14, Folder 258)
  - Page, William: note from Bank of Rutland demanding payment, 1828 (Box 14, Folder 259)
  - Phillips, George W.: sermons, 1897-1900, undated (Box 14, Folder 260)
  - Rider family: crest and genealogy, undated (Box 15, Folder 261)
  - Rider, Richard Price, 1909 (Box 15, Folder 262)
  - Rider, Richard Price: poetry, 1858-1912 (Box 15, Folder 263)
  - Todd family, undated (Box 15, Folder 264)
  - Winslow family, undated (Box 15, Folder 265)
  - Wright, Frank Hall: memorial sermon by Rev. William Crow, 1922 (Box 15, Folder 266)
- Diaries, 1893-1943; Series III; 1.0' (3 boxes)
  Series III, Boxes 16-18, contains eighteen diaries kept by Elizabeth Merwin Roe Page and one diary of attorney's appointments kept by Alfred Rider Page. The diaries are arranged in chronological order.
  - Diary, 1893-1894 (Box 16, Folder 267)
  - Diaries of Indian mission work, 1902-1908 (Box 16, Folder 268-273)
  - Diary, 1909-1913 (Box 16, Folder 274)
  - Diaries of Indian mission work, 1909-1912 (Box 16, Folder 275-277)
  - Diary, 1914-1918 (Box 16, Folder 278)
  - Diaries, 1919-1933 (Box 17, Folder 279-281)
  - Diary: Alfred R. Page, 1931 (Box 17, Folder 282)
  - Diary, 1932 (Box 17, Folder 283)
  - Diaries, 1934-1943 (Box 18, Folder 284-285)
- Business and Legal Papers, 1880-1943; Series IV; 1.25' (3 boxes)
  Series IV consists of three boxes of alphabetically arranged financial and legal papers relating to the Page family.
  - Bank records: Corn Exchange Bank, 1924-1932 (Box 19, Folder 286-289)
  - Bank statements: Grace J. Lauman, 1941-1943 (Box 19, Folder 290)
  - Check stubs, 1926-1931 (Box 19, Folder 291-295)
  - Check stubs, 1932 (Box 20, Folder 296)
  - Checks: Corn Exchange Bank, 1927-1932 (Box 20, Folder 297-302)
  - Columbia Trust Company, 1917-1919 (Box 20, Folder 303)
  - Corn Exchange Bank, 1919-1931 (Box 20, Folder 303)
  - Empire Trust Company, 1921-1923 (Box 20, Folder 304)
  - The Farmer's Loan and Trust Company, 1918-1923 (Box 20, Folder 305)
  - Household bills, 1894-1943 (Box 21, Folder 306)
  - Income tax materials, 1923-1943 (Box 21, Folder 307)
  - Insurance policies, 1916-1931, undated (Box 21, Folder 308)
  - Lake Bomoseen house, Castleton, Vt.: tax bills, 1915-1937 (Box 21, Folder 309)
  - Legal records, 1893-1935 (Box 21, Folder 310-312)
  - McMillan, Mary C., 1921-1926 (Box 21, Folder 313)
  - Manchester, Vt. House
    - Bills, 1916-1941 (Box 21, Folder 314)
    - Inventories, undated (Box 21, Folder 315)
    - Leases, deeds, and agreements, 1916-1933 (Box 21, Folder 316)
    - Tax bills and records, 1916-1937 (Box 21, Folder 317)
  - Page, Alfred Rider: bills, cancelled checks, receipts, 1880-1895 (Box 21, Folder 318)
  - Page, Elizabeth Merwin Roe: business and legal papers, 1896-1942 (Box 21, Folder 319)
  - Perkins, E. C.: business correspondence and records, 1918-1935, undated (Box 21, Folder 320)
  - The Railroad Co-Operative Building & Loan Association, 1901 (Box 21, Folder 321)
  - 2202 Loring Place
    - Financial records, 1911-1914 (Box 21, Folder 322)
    - Mortgages, tax receipts, etc., 1894-1930 (Box 21, Folder 323)
    - Receipts for work done, 1911-1924 (Box 21, Folder 324)
    - Tax bills, 1912-1927 (Box 21, Folder 325)
- Printed Works, 1865-1941; Series V; 2.5' (6 boxes)
  PRINTED WORKS, Boxes 22-27, is arranged alphabetically by type of printed material and alphabetically by author and title within each subject.
  - Books
    - Beautiful Beckoning Hands, 1887 (Box 22, Folder 326)
    - Bible, 1878 (Box 22, Folder 327)
    - Christian Companionship, 1865 (Box 22, Folder 328)
    - Cicero, A Dialogue on Old Age, 1880 (Box 22, Folder 329)
    - Davies, W. H., The Sunday Scholar's Service of Sacred Song, undated (Box 22, Folder 330)
    - Dorr, Julia C. R., The Legend of The Baboushka, undated (Box 22, Folder 331)
    - Drummond, Henry, Addresses, 1891 (Box 22, Folder 332)
    - Farrar, Frederic W., Heaven in Earthly Homes, undated (Box 23, Folder 333)
    - Founders of Church and State, 1928 (Box 23, Folder 334)
    - Franklin, Benjamin, Poor Richard's Almanack, 1914 (Box 23, Folder 335)
    - Gordon, A. J., In Christ, 1880 (Box 23, Folder 336)
    - The Gospel Choir, 1885 (Box 23, Folder 337)
    - Guide to the Campus of Cornell University, 1920 (Box 23, Folder 338)
    - Hammond's Comprehensive Atlas of the World, 1914 (Box 23, Folder 339)
    - Hudson-Fulton Celebration, 1909 (Box 24, Folder 340)
    - In Memoriam: Theodore Roosevelt, 1919 (Box 24, Folder 341)
    - Jerome, Irene H., One Year's Sketch-Book, 1886 (Box 24, Folder 342)
    - Kempis, Thomas À., Imitation of Christ, undated (Box 24, Folder 343)
    - Poems of Home Life, undated (Box 24, Folder 343)
    - Meyer, F. B., Christian Living, undated (Box 24, Folder 344)
    - Meyer, F. B., Shepherd Psalm, undated (Box 24, Folder 344)
    - Miner, Roy Waldo, Exhibition Halls of the Museum of Natural History, 1939 (Box 24, Folder 345)
    - Murray, Andrew, Like Christ, 1895 (Box 24, Folder 346)
    - Nesbit, Wilbur D., If the Heart Be Young, 1911 (Box 24, Folder 347)
    - "The Ninety-First Psalm", undated (Box 25, Folder 348)
    - Page, Charles N., History and Genealogy of the Page Family, 1911 (Box 25, Folder 349)
    - Porter, Rose, A Gift of Peace, 1894 (Box 25, Folder 350)
    - Second Baptist Church, Liberty, Missouri, 1909 (Box 25, Folder 351)
    - The Songs of the Roses, undated (Box 25, Folder 352)
    - Soule, John B. L, Polychords, 1882 (Box 25, Folder 353)
    - Spurgeon, C. H., Readings by Evening, undated (Box 25, Folder 354)
    - The Standard Engine, 1924 (Box 26, Folder 355)
    - Tales for Tots, undated (Box 26, Folder 356)
    - Taylor, Ida Scott, In His Name, undated (Box 26, Folder 357)
    - White, William, The Student's Manual of Medical Electricity, 1869 (Box 26, Folder 358)
  - Leaflets, 1915, undated (Box 26, Folder 359)
  - Magazines
    - The Book News Monthly, 1913 (Box 26, Folder 360)
    - Clippings, 1913-1929, undated (Box 26, Folder 361)
    - Fleet's Review, 1929-1930 (Box 26, Folder 362-366)
    - The Literary Magazine, 1886-1887 (Box 27, Folder 367)
    - Telephone Topics, 1938 (Box 27, Folder 368)
    - The Trend, 1925 (Box 27, Folder 369)
  - Maps
    - Illinois, undated (Box 27, Folder 370)
    - New York City, 1922, undated (Box 27, Folder 371)
    - Miscellaneous, 1871, undated (Box 27, Folder 372)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1917-1936, undated (Box 27, Folder 373-376)
  - Pamphlets
    - The Battle Creek Diet System, undated (Box 27, Folder 377)
    - A Calendar of Beautiful Thoughts, 1912 (Box 27, Folder 378)
    - Carruth, William Herbert, Each in his Own Tongue, 1925 (Box 27, Folder 379)
    - Edwards, Harry Stillwell, Eneas Africanus, 1920 (Box 27, Folder 380)
    - Hand-Book of the Hall of Fame, 1927 (Box 27, Folder 381)
    - Harrison, Norman B., His Bequest, 1931 (Box 27, Folder 381)
    - Harrison, Norman B., His Peace, 1930 (Box 27, Folder 381)
    - Sinking to Sleep, 1927 (Box 27, Folder 383)
    - Miscellaneous, 1895-1941, undated (Box 27, Folder 384-385)
  - Poetry, undated (Box 27, Folder 386-387)
- Photographs, 1863-1922; Series VI; 4.25' (6 boxes)
  Series VI, PHOTOGRAPHS, is contained in Boxes 28-33 of the Page Family Papers. Boxes 28-29 have alphabetically arranged pictures of people, while Boxes 29-31 contain pictures of places. Boxes 32-33 contain Oversize material.
  - People
    - Burton portraits, 1898, undated (Box 28, Folder 388)
    - Carlinville, Illinois portraits, 1890, undated (Box 28, Folder 389)
    - Clark portraits, undated (Box 28, Folder 390)
    - Coolidge, Calvin, undated (Box 28, Folder 391)
    - Friends and relatives, 1877-1921, undated (Box 28, Folder 392-394)
    - Harris, Elizabeth Merwin Page, undated (Box 28, Folder 395)
    - Kellogg portraits, undated (Box 28, Folder 396)
    - Lambert family, undated (Box 28, Folder 397)
    - Page family, undated (Box 28, Folder 398-399)
    - Page family pictures, undated (Box 28, Folder 400-402)
    - Page family snapshots, undated (Box 28, Folder 403)
    - Page portraits, undated (Box 28, Folder 404-405)
    - Page, Alfred Rider, 1881, 1922, undated (Box 29, Folder 406-407)
    - Page, Angeline Rider, undated (Box 29, Folder 408)
    - Page, Elizabeth Merwin Roe, 1882, undated (Box 29, Folder 409-410)
    - Page, Helen Frances, 1863 (Box 29, Folder 411)
    - Page, Helen Wickham, 1888, undated (Box 29, Folder 412)
    - Rider portraits, 1883, 1887, undated (Box 29, Folder 413)
    - Rider, Richard Price, 1915, undated (Box 29, Folder 414)
    - Roe family, undated (Box 29, Folder 415)
    - Roe, Mary Wickham, undated (Box 29, Folder 416)
    - Schauffler, Marjorie Page, undated (Box 29, Folder 417)
    - Unidentified portraits, undated (Box 29, Folder 418-421)
    - Wickham family, 1884, undated (Box 29, Folder 422)
  - Places
    - Lake Bomoseen, Vt., undated (Box 29, Folder 423-425)
    - Manchester, Vt., undated (Box 30, Folder 426-427)
    - Miscellaneous pictures, undated (Box 30, Folder 428-429)
    - Mission photographs, undated (Box 30, Folder 430-431)
    - New York(State), undated (Box 30, Folder 432)
    - Page homestead in Rutland, Vt., undated (Box 30, Folder 433)
    - Panama Canal, undated (Box 30, Folder 434-435)
    - Panorama of the Hudson River, 1906 (Box 30, Folder 436)
    - Pictures of the orient, undated (Box 30, Folder 437)
    - Postcards, undated (Box 30, Folder 438-440)
    - Reproductions of paintings, undated (Box 30, Folder 441)
    - Reproductions of religious paintings, undated (Box 31, Folder 442)
    - Sierra Madre, Cal., undated (Box 31, Folder 443)
    - Snapshots
      - Caribbean, undated (Box 31, Folder 444-446)
      - New York City, undated (Box 31, Folder 447)
      - Page vacation trip, undated (Box 31, Folder 448-449)
      - Vermont, undated (Box 31, Folder 450)
      - Western United States, undated (Box 31, Folder 451-452)
    - Summer camping trip, undated (Box 31, Folder 453)
    - 2202 Loring Place, undated (Box 31, Folder 454)
    - Vermont, undated (Box 31, Folder 455)
    - Western United States, undated (Box 31, Folder 456)
  - Oversize
    - Rolled photographs, undated (Box 32, Folder 457)
    - Page, Alfred Rider
      - Admissions to bar, 1887, 1889 (Box 33, Folder 458)
      - Certificates and diplomas, 1901-1916 (Box 33, Folder 459)
      - Humerous, undated (Box 33, Folder 460)
      - Judicial appointments, 1915-1916 (Box 33, Folder 461)
      - The Press Scrap Book, 1909 (Box 33, Folder 462)
      - 2202 Loring Place, 1911 (Box 33, Folder 463)
    - Photographs
      - Page, Alfred Rider, 1909, undated (Box 33, Folder 464-467)
      - 2202 Loring Place, 1912 (Box 33, Folder 468)
      - Red Cross nursing staff, 1917-1918 (Box 33, Folder 469)
      - Rotogravure pictures, 1917, undated (Box 33, Folder 470)
- Additional Material, 1872-1944; 0.5' (1 box)
  The 1985 addition to the Page Family Papers has twelve folders of correspondence, eight folders of family papers, and two folders of religious books owned by Angeline Rider Page. The Addition was received from the Schauffler family of Sandy Spring, Maryland in Janurary 1985.
  The correspondence consists primarily of letters between Lillie Page and her daughter Marjorie Page Schauffler. They provide additional documentation of Lillie's eye problems, particularly in 1934, when she lost virtually all of her sight. Also included in the Addition is a short 1916 letter from Theodore Roosevelt to Alfred Page, a few 1920's letters concerning the Grenfell Association, and a 1943 tribute to Elizabeth M. Page from the Women's Board of Domestic Missions.
  Included among the family papers are two folders of estate papers, insurance policies, and recipes.
  - Correspondence, 1916-1943, undated (Box 34, Folder 1-11)
  - Letter fragments, undated (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Page, Alfred Rider: Announcement, undated (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Page, Elizabeth Merwin Roe
    - Agreement, 1940 (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - Calling cards, undated (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - Diary, 1933 (Box 34, Folder 16)
    - Estate of, 1943-1944 (Box 34, Folder 17-18)
    - Insurance policies, 1940-1942 (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - Recipes and miscellaneous, undated (Box 34, Folder 20)
  - The Changed Cross, and Other Religious Poems, 1872 (Box 34, Folder 21)
  - MacDuff, J. R., The Mind and Words of Jesus, 1874 (Box 34, Folder 22)